wa-democrats.org 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy | Washington State Democratic Party

The Washington State Democratic Party is committed to protecting your privacy. While using our website, you do not have to identify yourself or divulge personal information. If you should choose to give us your personal information, you decide the amount of information you provide. This Privacy Statement applies to data collection and usage on wa-democrats.org; it does not apply to other websites.

Personal information of all users is collected, used and disclosed as described in this Privacy Statement. Other websites linked to wa-democrats.org have their own privacy statements which can be viewed by clicking on the links.

## Collection of your Personal Information

When you sign up on wa-democrats.org, we may ask for your name, address, telephone number, email address, and other information. We use the information you provide to send you the latest news and updates from the Washington State Democrats. We work closely with Democratic candidates, parties and allied organizations and may share some basic contact information with them, and they may contact you.

When you sign one of our petitions: We treat your name, city, state, and any comments as public information. We may, for example, provide compilations of petitions, with your comments, to national leaders, without disclosing email addresses. We may also make comments along with your city and state available to the press and public online.

When you contribute money: Under state election law, we are required to make periodic filings that provide the Public Disclosure Commission with the following information on each contributor: name, address, amount of contribution, date of contribution, employer and occupation. For more information on the PDC, visit their website at [www.pdc.wa.gov](http://www.pdc.wa.gov/ "www.pdc.wa.gov").

Federal law requires us to collect and report your name, address, employer, occupation, and the amount of your contribution. We are required by federal law to collect and report the name, mailing address, occupation and name of employers of individuals whose contributions exceed $200 in a calendar year to the Federal Election Commission. These records are available to the public. However, they cannot be used by other organizations for fundraising. For additional information, visit the FEC website at [http://www.fec.gov](http://www.fec.gov/ "http://www.fec.gov").

## Use of your Personal Information

Wa-democrats.org collects and uses your personal information to operate wa-democrats.org and deliver the services you have requested. These services may include the display of customized content based upon the information wa-democrats.org has collected.

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing customer support, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information and are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with an appropriate law enforcement investigation, current judicial proceeding, court order or legal process served on our website.

## Control of your Personal Information

To contact us or unsubscribe via U.S. Mail: Send a letter with your full name and email address to: Washington State Democrats, PO Box 4027, Seattle, WA 98104

## Collection and Use of Children's Personal Information

We care about the safety and privacy of children online, and we comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulations establish United States federal law that protects the privacy of children using the Internet. We do not knowingly contact or collect personal information from children under 13. Our site is not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13, and we have designed our sites to block our knowing acceptance of information from children under 13 whenever age-related information is requested.

## How do we protect your information?

Our website has a number of security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information under our control. Computer systems have restricted access limited only to those persons and organizations necessary to the proper functioning of wa-democrats.org. This access applies to all electronic and physical security measures. Highly sensitive data including credit card information is additionally secured through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

## Use of Cookies

We use cookies to tailor your experience on our site according to the preferences you have specified. When you visit wa-democrats.org, your browser saves a tiny piece of information on your computer. This information personalizes and improves your experience online. Wa-democrats.org only accesses information set by wa-democrats.org. It is not possible and we do not attempt to access information from other websites. Our cookies do not contain any personal identifiable information.  
You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience all features of the wa-democrats.org site.

## IP Addresses and Log File Data

We log your IP address, which is the location of your computer or network on the Internet, for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. We also use page hits in the aggregate to track the popularity of pages that people visit in order to improve the quality of the site. There is no personal identifiable information collected in our log files.

## Enforcement of this Privacy Statement

If you have questions regarding this statement, you should first contact JayInslee.com by postal mail to Washington State Democrats, PO Box 4027, Seattle, WA 98104

## Changes to this Statement

Wa-democrats.org will occasionally update this Privacy Statement. When wa-democrats.org posts changes to this Statement, you will see the word "updated" next to the Privacy Statement link on the front page of wa-democrats.org. If there are material changes to this Statement or in how we will use your personal information, wa-democrats.org will prominently post such changes prior to implementing the change. We encourage you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how wa-democrats.org is protecting your information.

## Contact Information

Wa-democrats.org welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. If you believe that wa-democrats.org has not adhered to this Statement, please contact us by postal mail.

Washington State Democrats  
PO Box 4027  
Seattle, WA 98104
